Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/aliparker-79191427 (LinkedIn) www.alilouiseparker.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Event Management
Event Planning
Sports Marketing

Certifications

Launch Event Coordinator Exam Wedding Assistant Exam Launch Event Assistant Exam

Ali Parker

Co Founder at The Broad Collective || Experiential & Brand Marketing, Strategy and Production

Atlanta, Georgia, United States

Summary

Strategic marketing and business development leader with 10+ years of experience and a demonstrated history of internal strategy, experiential marketing, brand strategy, creative direction and team management. Out-of-the-box thinker with a talent for connecting people, teams, and brands to bring ideas to life.

Experience

The Broad Collective

Co-founder / Co-owner || Experiential & Brand Marketing, Strategy and Production

January 2018 - Present (7 years 2 months)

Austin, Texas Area

Built an agency from the ground up by optimizing existing relationships, creating new partnerships and 10+ years of industry knowledge which grew revenue over 60% year over year (pre COVID19).

Freelance

Experiential and Creative Producer April 2017 - December 2017 (9 months)

Greater Chicago Area

Hired by agencies and brands to conceptualize and produce experiential marketing campaigns that increased brand awareness among key demographics.

- -Headed a team of creative freelancers and collaborated with clients to produce three to four projects simultaneously
- -Demonstrated professionalism and knowledge by repeatedly being recruited by the same clients

BeCore

4 years 3 months

Director of Production

January 2016 - March 2017 (1 year 3 months)

Greater Los Angeles Area

Managed 12 key accounts and a team of 10+ at an Experiential Marketing agency based in Los Angeles.

- -Member of the executive team that directly influenced company strategy and overall goals by researching industry standards and practices and ensuring we met or exceeded in all areas
- -Advocated for updated company benefits to improve employee retention and burnout which led to retaining producers for 2+ years in a high-turnover industry
- -Orchestrated weekly meetings to ensure cross-functional collaboration with creative and business development teams as well as forecasting future revenue and growth
- -Represented the executive team onsite at events to oversee production team and seek out new business opportunities

Recent BeCore Honors:

- 2013 Summit Creative Award / Experiential Marketing Gold / Pima Air & Space Museum with BBDOSF
- 2013 Summit Creative Award / Experiential Marketing Bronze / Nike Chosen Tour (Winter)
- 2013 Summit Creative Award / Sales Presentation Silver / Columbia Editors'
 Conference
- 2012 Cannes Lion Award Winner- Gold & Silver / Pima Air & Space Museum with BBDOSF
- 2012 Ex Award / Best Multi Venue Consumer Event / Nike Chosen Tour (Summer)
- 2012 Summit Creative Award / Gold Green Marketing Barefoot Wine and Surfruder Foundation
- 2011 Summit International Award / Experiential Marketing Innovator / Nike Chosen Tour (Summer)
- Named a Promo 100 Agency
- Named to the 2012 Inc. 500I5000 List
- Named one of LA Business Journal's 2012 Top 100 Fastest Growing Privately Owned Companies

Account Director

October 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 3 months)

Oversaw accounts and directed internal production and creative teams to align with the brand teams for Mark Anthony Brands and Teva.

-Grew accounts revenue by building relationships with clients, seeking out new opportunities with different brands under the umbrella and hitting KPIs on projects which led to increased budgets year over year -Increased average profit margin on projects by 5%

Senior Producer

January 2013 - September 2014 (1 year 9 months)

Greater Los Angeles Area

Strategized and executed 30+ events for Red Bull, Nike, Muscle Milk, NASCAR, DC and other key brands including the Red Bull Activation at US Open of Surfing, Energy Station at Red Bull MotoGP, Energy Station at Red Bull X Fighters, Nike NTC Week.

- -Trained a team of 5+ Assistant Producers and Project Coordinators
- -Continuously met and exceeded client expectations and hit all KPIs specific to the project which led to year over year repeat projects, client retention and account growth

Red Frog Events

2 years 10 months

Event Director | Warrior Dash

May 2010 - October 2012 (2 years 6 months)

Planned and executed over 25 domestic and international events within the active entertainment industry and created all pre-event reports, budgets and data to ensure accurate onsite execution.

- -Developed an event strategy and RFP used to present to local governments both domestically and in Australia for approval on future event locations
- -Built relationships with key vendors that translated into over \$100K in savings per year
- -Spearheaded team to run first P&L & set of analytics on flagship event to understand overall profit margin and made recommendations to CEOs for efficiencies

Production Manager || Firefly Music Festival January 2010 - May 2010 (5 months)
Chicago, IL

Created the on-site logistics and operations plan and led the on-site BOH production team for a successful first year, three-day festival with attendance of 30K/day and headlined by The Black Keys, John Legend, Jack White and The Killers.

- -Researched and vetted key vendors for staging and production leading to a multi-contract agreement with selected vendors
- -Established roles and responsibilities for on-site BOH production team
- -Core member of initial planning team responsible for site visits, permitting and operations

Mad Eagle: A Unique Boutique Manager/Visual Merchandiser November 2005 - December 2009 (4 years 2 months)

- Assisted owner in discovering new lines and ordering and processing shipments
- · Designed window and in-store displays
- Hosted private in-store parties for select clientele
- · Styled outfits for magazine shoots as well as select clients
- Created relationships with loyal clients and acted as a personal shopper to many
- Communicated the uniqueness of many of our brands as well as created advertisements to inform current and future clientele of sales and promotions
- Assisted brides in designing and selecting jewelry for their weddings

Education

Michigan State University

Bachelors of Arts Degree, Marketing · (2005 - 2009)